Inventory of the William W. McClellan papers, 1924-1960
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
William W. McClellan papers
1924-1960
McClellan, William W.
02153
.45 cubic feet (1 box)
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Biography of William W. McClellan
William W. McClellan was an employee of the United States Bureau of Indian Affairs in New Mexico for over 30 years. He joined the BIA in 1927 as a general foreman for irrigation at the Shiprock Agency and in 1937 transferred to a similar position at the Navajo Agency. In 1941, he became the Agricultural Extension Agent at the United Pueblo Agency. He supervised the irrigation systems of the Hogback Irrigation Project at the Shiprock Agency.
Scope and Content
The collection includes pictorial crop and construction reports for the Hogback Project (1924-1933) and pictorial reports for the Alamo and Canoncito Navajo areas (1946, 1955-1960).
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions on the materials for research purposes, and the collection is open to the public.
Related Materials
There are no known other archival collections created by William W. McClellan at the date of processing.
Acquisition Information
Access Terms
Hogback Irrigation Project (N.M.); Irrigation -- Navajo Indian Reservation.; Agriculture -- Navajo Indian Reservation.; Water-supply -- Navajo Indian Reservation.; Dams -- Navajo Indian Reservation.; Agriculture -- New Mexico.; Irrigation -- New Mexico.; Water-supply -- New Mexico.; Dams -- New Mexico.; Navajo Indian Reservation.; Alamo (N.M.); Canoncito (N.M.);;;;; United States. Bureau of Indian Affairs. Navajo Area Office.; United States. Bureau of Indian Affairs. Shiprock Agency.
Agriculture and Natural Resources; Water and Water Rights; Politics, Government, and Law; Native Americans
Container List
- Pictorial Reports:
  - 1. Crop report for the Hogback Project at Shiprock, N.M., 1924-1929, under the Fifth Irrigation Service. (No photos with this report. Were unable to be obtained.) (Box 1)
  - 2. Hogback Project, Shiprock, N.M. on the San Juan River. Photos and brief history by W.W. McClellan. 1930. (Box 1)
  - 3. Hogback Project. Indians at work, cleaning the canal, and construction of jetties along the San Juan River bank for protection of farming land. 1932. (Box 1)
  - 4. Crop report for the Hogback Project. Photos of crops and activities of the project. 1933. (Box 1)
  - 5. Diversion dam on the Lower Captain Tom Wash. Photos of construction work done by the Fifth Irrigation District under supervision of W.W. McClellan on the Navajo Reservation. (Box 1)
  - 6. Alamo and Canoncito Areas. Report of Activities. 1946. (Box 1)
  - 7. Alamo-Canoncito, Navajo Areas. Annual Extension Pictorial Reports for 1955, 1956, 1957, 1958, 1959 and 1960. (Xerox copies of these particular reports are being made available for donor.), 1955-1960 (Box 1)
- Citation (copy of)
  - "For Meritorious Service, William W. McClellan," November 6, 1958. From Fred A. Senton, The Secretary of the Interior, Washington. (Box Biographical Files, Folder B-M132-ww)
  - Letter -- To Mr. William W. McClellan, from the Commissioner of the Dept. of the Interior, presenting the above Citation. Same Date. (Box Biographical Files, Folder B-M132-ww)
- Certificates (copies of)
  - To: William W. McClellan, hereby awarded this certificate of honor for Meritorious Service. From the United States Department of the Interior, November 1958. (Box Biographical Files, Folder B-M132-ww)
  - To: William W. McClellan. From the Imperial Council of the Ancient Arabic Order of the Nobles of the Mystic Shrine. May 26, 1944. (Box Biographical Files, Folder B-M132-ww)